High-Level Shinobi
（マダラ）ダンゾウめ
死ぬ前に己で　シスイの目を。
That Danzo…
He destroyed Shisui's eye
before he died.
（ナルト）お前は　オレの。
You've been…
目標になった。
my goal.
何にもなかった俺が
つながりを持てた。
I had nothing,
but I built bonds with Team 7.
第七班で。
お前と　サクラちゃんと
一緒になって。
With you and Sakura.
((うわ～！
（サスケ）うわ～！
（ハク）これで　カタをつけます。
I'll end it with this!
《なんだと　ナルトに！？
What?! He's after Naruto?!
間に合え！》
I have to make it!
You'll never stop…
being a burden.
まったく　お前は。
いつまでたっても
足手まといだぜ。
サスケ　お前。
Sasuke, you…
なんで。
Why?
《俺をかばって？》
Why did you protect me?
なんて顔してやがんだよ。
Why are you looking at me
like that?
このウスラトンカチ。
You loser.
Why…did you…?
なんで　俺なんか。
よけいなお世話だ！
Mind your own business!
Like…
知るかよ　そんなこと。
I care.
お前なんか　大嫌いだったのによ。
I…used to hate you.
サスケ！
お前は　死ぬな。
Sasuke…
You better not die.
サスケ！
Sasuke…
(サスケ！！))
Sasuke!
((うわあ！
よう。
Hey!
(ケガはねえかよ　ビビリ君))
Are you hurt, Scaredy Cat?
((うお～！
（再不斬）フン。
(ここだ～！))
Over here!
You're the one messing up
our teamwork!
((チームワーク乱してんのは
テメエだよ　サスケ！
いっつも出しゃばりやがって！
You're always showing off!
Speak for yourself, loser!
それはお前だ　ウスラトンカチ！
そんなに俺に
借りを作りたくねえならな。
If you don't want to owe me,
you should just become
stronger than me.
(俺より強くなりゃいいだろうが))
よぉ　ケガはねえかよ　ビビリ君。
Hey, are you hurt, Scaredy Cat?
♪～
うっ！
うわぁ～！
Here you go!
Thanks for waiting!
（テウチ）ヘイ　お待ち！
Imagine that,
the three of you treating me.
（カカシ）お前らが　３人揃って
おごってくれるなんて→
I wouldn't be surprised
if it snowed.
雪でも降るんじゃ…。
– It totally worked!
(（みんな）大成功！))
千鳥！
Chidori!
Even if I have to beat you to
a pulp and drag you,
お前を　ボッコボコにして
引きずってでも連れて帰る！
I'll bring you back!
おりゃっ！
♪～
I wanted to be strong
and cool like you.
((お前みたく
強くかっこよくなりたくて→
That's why I kept chasing
after you.
ずっと　お前のあとを
追いかけてた。
I'm really glad I met you.
俺は　お前と会えて
本当によかった。
Naruto…
ナルト…　お前が　今さら
何を言おうと　俺は変わらない。
You can't change me,
no matter what you say to me now.
俺は　お前も　里のヤツらも
一人残らず　全員を殺す！
I'm going to kill
each and every person in the Leaf,
including you!
うちはの復讐をとげるために…。
And I'll get revenge for
the Uchiha Clan!
Is that really the only way?
なぁ　本当に
そんな道しかねえのか？
Yes.
そうだ。
行き着くところ
お前の選択は→
So your only choices are
to kill me and
俺を殺して
里を守った英雄になるか→
become the hero who
saved the village,
or to be killed by me and
become known as just a loser!
俺に殺されて
ただの負け犬になるかだ。
サスケ…　俺は　そう思っちゃいねえ。
Sasuke…
I don't believe that.
俺は　負け犬になんかならねえし→
I'm not going to be the loser,
or the hero who killed you!
お前を殺した
英雄なんかにもならねえ！
その　どっちでもねえよ！
Neither one's gonna happen!
(俺は…))
I…
（ゼツ）おっと！
Whoa!
お前は　いつの間に…。
You!
When did you—?
もう随分と前から
お前についている。
I've been tagging along
for quite a while.
本当は
お前に気づかれないようにって→
Tobi told me to make sure
you didn't notice me.
トビに言われてたんだけどね。
どう見ても　これピンチだから。
But, since you were in a crisis…
《そろそろ呼んだほうがいいかな。
I should summon him soon.
It doesn't seem like
he's going to retreat quietly.
素直には退きそうにもないし》
ナルト　お前は帰れって言ったでしょ。
Naruto…
I told you to go back
to the village.
これで　ハッキリした。
Now…
it's all clear.
戦争前に輪廻眼の回収を
さっさとやっておくか。
I'd better collect the Rinnegan
before the war begins.
サスケ　ピンチだよ。　どうする？
Sasuke's in a bind.
What do you want to do?
ハッキリした？
いったい何のことだ　ナルト。
"It's all clear"?
What do you mean, Naruto?
どういうことだ　サスケ。
What's going on, Sasuke?
I told you to go home and rest.
帰って休めと言ったはずだが。
《マダラ…》
Madara…
九尾か。
The Nine-Tails, huh?
どうにも　お前たちは→
It seems you cannot suppress
the urge to fight
２人揃えば戦いを
我慢できないようだな。
when you two get together.
九尾を狩るには
ちゃんとした場を設けてやる。
I'll arrange a proper place
for you to hunt the Nine-Tails.
今は退くぞ。
For now, we retreat.
代わりに僕がやるよ。
I'll fight in your stead.
どうせ九尾の人柱力は
狩らないといけないんだし。
Since we need the Nine-Tails
Jinchuriki anyway.
Madara as well as Zetsu?
《マダラにゼツか。
サスケにべったりだな。
They're sticking close to Sasuke.
だが　こうなってくると
俺一人では　きつい。
This is going to be tough
all by myself.
どうする？》
What should I do?
ゼツ。　お前じゃ
ナルトを捕まえるのはムリだ。
Zetsu… You can't capture Naruto.
戦闘タイプじゃないお前に→
The Nine-Tails will be too much
for a non-combat type like you.
九尾はきつい。
九尾は　サスケにやらせる。
I'm going to let Sasuke
get the Nine-Tails.
It's for my enjoyment as well.
俺の余興も兼ねてな。
ええ　そうなの？
Oh, is that so?
But I'm concerned about Kisame.
それより　鬼鮫が気になる。
そろそろ　そっちへ行け。
So go to him.
黒と合流してな。
And rendezvous with Black Zetsu.
Okay, okay, I understand.
はいはい　わかったよ。
ナルト。
Naruto!
うん　大丈夫だってばよ。
I'm all right.
ただ　サスケにちゃんと→
But I need to make sure
I say something to Sasuke.
言葉で言っておきたいことが
あるんだ。
行くぞ　サスケ。
Let's go, Sasuke.
Wait.
待て。
サスケ　覚えてるか？
Sasuke… Do you remember?
昔　終末の谷で
お前が俺に言ったことをよ。
Do you remember what you said
to me long ago in the Final Valley?
一流の忍ならってやつだ。
The thing about high-level shinobi.
((一流の忍同士なら→
When two shinobi are
of a high enough level,
拳を一度交えただけで
互いの心の内が読めちまう。
they can read each other's thoughts
through no more than
a trade of blows.
They don't need to say a word.
口には出さなくともだ。
お前は甘いな　ナルト。
You're naïve, Naruto.
どうだ？
So tell me…
Were you able to read what
was inside of my heart?
お前には
本当の心の内が読めたか？
(この　俺の！))
直接ぶつかって→
Clashing face-to-face.
Just now, we learned things from
just trading blows with each other.
今はお互い
いろいろ　わかっちまう。
俺たちは
一流の忍になれたってことだ。
It means we've become
high-level shinobi.
お前も　俺も。
You and me.
サスケ。
Sasuke…
お前も→
Were you able to read…
本当の心の内が読めたのかよ？
what was inside
of my heart?
この　俺のよ。
And you saw it, didn't you?
それに　見えただろう？
That if you and I fight…
お前と俺が戦えば…。
二人とも死ぬ。
we will both die.
サスケ…
お前が木ノ葉に攻めてくりゃ→
Sasuke…
If you attack the Hidden Leaf,
I will have to fight you.
俺はお前と戦わなきゃならねえ。
憎しみは　それまでとっとけ。
Save your hatred until then.
それは　そんときに
俺に全部ぶつけろ。
At that time, throw all of
your hatred at me.
The only one who can
handle all that hatred…
お前の憎しみを
受けてやれんのは→
俺しかいねえ。
is me.
Only I can fulfill that duty!
その役目は　俺しかできねえ。
そんときは
俺もお前の憎しみを背負って→
And on that day,
I'll bear the burden of
your hate and die with you!
一緒に死んでやる。
何なんだ？　ナルト。
What is it with you, Naruto?
Just what the hell do you want?!
テメエはいったい何がしてえんだよ！
何で俺に　そこまでこだわる！
Why are you so fixated on me?!
Because you're my friend!
友達だからだ。
サスケ　お前とわかりあうには
一筋縄じゃいかねえって→
Sasuke…
I knew from the moment we first met
that it was going to take more
than just ordinary means
to understand you.
初めて会ったときから
わかってた。
拳でわかりあうのが→
Exchanging fists is how
we understand each other.
お前とのやり方なのは
間違いねえしよ。
That's for sure.
さっきも言ったけどよ。
Like I said just now…
It means we've become
high-level shinobi.
もうお互い
一流の忍になれたことだしな。
《わかりあえば　お前の憎しみも→
Once we understand each other,
your hatred will go away.
The same way that I changed
after meeting Iruka Sensei.
俺が　イルカ先生に会って
変われたみてえに》
俺は　まだあきらめてねえ。
I'm not giving up yet.
I'm taking you back
to Hidden Leaf Village!
俺は　お前を
木ノ葉に連れ戻すことを→
That's something I'll never give up on!
絶対にあきらめねえってばよ！
《サクラ：ナルト　アンタ…》
Naruto…you…
ヘッ　けど　グチャグチャお前に言うのは
やめだってばよ！
Well, I've rambled on enough.
ったくよ　口下手の俺が
説教なんて柄じゃなかったぜ。
Damn it.
A poor talker like me lecturing you,
it's not my style.
ヘヘッ。
If we both end up dying…
もし行きつくところまでいって
お互い死んだとしても→
うちはでもなく
九尾の人柱力でもなくなってよ→
You won't be an Uchiha and
I won't be the Nine-Tail's Jinchuriki.
We'll be free of all our burdens.
何も背負わなくなりゃ
あの世で本当にわかりあえら！
And we'll finally be able to understand
each other in the next world!
俺は変わりはしねえ。
I don't plan on changing.
お前と　わかりあう気もねえ
死ぬ気もねえ。
Nor am I interested
in understanding you.
And I don't plan on dying!
死ぬのは　お前だ。
You're the one who's going to die.
死ぬなら一緒だ　サスケ。
If I die, we both die, Sasuke.
フッ。
いいだろう
お前をいちばんに殺してやる。
Fine then! I'll kill you first.
俺ってば　まだお前に　ちゃんと
認めてもらってねえからよ。
It's clear you still haven't
acknowledged me yet.
Enough, Naruto.
I'll take Sasuke on.
もういい　ナルト
サスケは　俺がやる。
You have your precious dream
of becoming the Hokage.
お前には　火影になるって
大切な夢がある。
サスケの道連れで
お前が潰れることは…。
I can't let Sasuke take
you down with him.
How can I become the Hokage
仲間一人救えねえヤツが→
if I can't even save one friend?!
火影になんてなれるかよ。
I'll fight Sasuke!
サスケとは　俺がやる！
《ナルトは覚悟を決めて
この場にいる》
Naruto stands here
with clear resolve.
((俺もお前の憎しみ背負って
一緒に死んでやる))
I'll bear the burden of
your hate and die with you!
《私なんかの甘い覚悟とは違う。
Compared to him,
my resolve is weak.
I'm a shinobi.
私は忍のくせに泣いてばかりで→
Yet all I do is cry and
keep relying on Naruto.
ナルトに　ずっと頼りきってて→
それを振りきったつもりで
ここへ来たのに→
I came here thinking
I was past all that.
But I haven't prepared myself
for anything.
覚悟もできてなくて。
何もできない　何も言えない。
I can't do a thing.
I can't say anything.
All I can do…
私にできることは…》
is trust them!
《サクラ：二人を信じること》
わかった　ナルト
サスケは　お前に任せる。
All right, Naruto.
I'll leave Sasuke to you.
However, Sakura…
だが　サクラ…　俺の体を頼む。
Watch over my body.
I'll get rid of Madara
once and for all.
マダラは　ここで俺が処理する。
神威！
Kamui!
Forget it, Kakashi.
やめておけ　カカシ。
そんな術は俺には効かない。
A jutsu like that won't work on me.
いくぞ　サスケ。
Let's go, Sasuke.
マダラ　あとで話がある。
Madara, I'll talk to you later.
いつでも来い　サスケ。
I'll be ready anytime, Sasuke.
（マダラ）話とは何だ？
What did you want
to talk to me about?
イタチの目をもらう。
I want Itachi's eyes.
やっと　その気になったか。
So you finally made up your mind.
須佐能乎の使いすぎだな。
You've overused the Susano'o.
I'm aware that you can barely see.
もう　ろくに見えないのも
わかっていた。
いいタイミングだ。
It's perfect timing.
すぐに移植してくれ。
Transplant them right away.
You're in a hurry.
What's going on?
急いでるな。
どうしたというのだ？
俺は全力で　ナルトを潰す！
I'm going use every ounce of
my strength to crush Naruto!
そして　ヤツのすべてを
否定してやる…　それだけだ。
I'll eradicate him completely!
That's all.
《サクラ：ナルト　いつもありがとう。
Naruto… Thank you, as always!
アンタのおかげで　私はまだ→
Because of you,
I can still hope for the day
第七班みんなで笑い合える先を
あきらめないでいられる》
that we'll laugh together again
as Team 7.
なにっ！？
– What?!
– Wha—?!
ナルト！
Naruto!
頬の傷　これだな。
A scratch on his cheek.
This must be the cause.
えっ　これって…　じゃあ！
Then it's…
((ナルト！
ナルト！))
Naruto?!
Naruto…
（サクラ）あのとき
私の毒つきのクナイで！？
It's from the poison-dipped
kunai knife I used earlier.
どうやら　そうみたいね。
Seems like it.
すぐに解毒してくれ　サクラ。
You need to administer
the antidote right away, Sakura!
I'm taking you to Hidden Leaf Village.
（カカシ）キミは　木ノ葉へ連れていくよ。
おとなしくしててね。
So please behave yourself.
（香燐）今さら　何もしやしねえよ。
I wouldn't try anything at this point.
まだ気持悪い…。
I still feel sick.
A-Are you all right?
だ…　大丈夫？
わっ…　吐きそう？
You're gonna throw up!
《コイツが…　うずまきナルトか》
– So that's…
– Hold on a minute!
やるぞ　いいな。
やってくれ。
《兄さん…。
俺が　木ノ葉を潰す！》
（くもじい）もしもし
そこの　あなた。
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
今回は　天竜川じゃ。
（くもみ）天竜川？
南アルプスを望む
雄大な景色や→
太古の自然が作り出した
数多くの河川→
山岳地形などが
いっぱいあるんじゃ。
うわあ！
更には天空の秘境生活や→